Guide to the Chester R. Middlesworth Awards Collection, 1988-2010
Duke University. University Archives
Chester R. Middlesworth Awards records 1988-ongoig
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Rare Book, Manuscript and Special Collections Library.
2.3 linear feet Extent: 500 Items
The Middlesworth Awards have been established to encourage and recognize excellence of research, analysis, and writing by Duke University students in the use of primary sources and rare materials held by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library of Duke University. This collection contains prize winning papers, information about the prize, nomination forms, correspondence and other records.
uamiddle
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Chester R. Middlesworth Awards Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in May 2010.
Historical Note
The Middlesworth Awards have been established to encourage and recognize excellence of research, analysis, and writing by Duke University students in the use of primary sources and rare materials held by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library of Duke University. The awards are granted annually to the authors of the best undergraduate and graduate student papers based largely on materials from the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library. Funding for the awards has been provided by Chester P. Middlesworth (A.B., 1949) of Statesville, North Carolina.
Collection Overview
This collection contains prize winning papers, information about the prize, nomination forms, correspondence and other records.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- Awards; Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, 1988-2010, (4 boxes)
  - General Information and Nominating Forms, undated (Box 1)
  - Award Correspondence, Announcements and Nomination Forms, 1988-2009
  - The Household of Faith: Maria Dyer Davies and the Search for Evangelical Man, 1851-1855, Kleit, David H., 1988
  - A Family's Struggle with the Civil War: Margaret Bradley Willard Papers, Mallett, Katherine, 1988
  - Age-Related Declines in Syntactic Complexity: A Follow-Up Study on the Mitigating Effects of Life-Time Education and Practice of Language Skills, Strand, Stacey Joellen, 1988
  - I Cannot Account for So Long a Silence: The Record of Self and Culture in the Ellen Peirce Papers, Thomas, Amy M., 1988
  - Race, Class, and Poverty in North Carolina, 1828-1861, Bolton, Charles, 1989
  - The Self-Esteem of a Professional Woman Writer: Eliza Ann Dupuy, Robert Bonner, and The New York Ledger, Childers, Peter, 1989
  - The Pastor's Wife's Manuscript: A Critical Text and Commentary, Fulton, Peter, 1989
  - The Health and Health Care of the Antebellum Slave, Golden, Willian Christopher, 1989
  - The Diaries and Letters of Emma Bryant: Voices of a Nineteenth-Century Woman, Lesjak, Carolyn, 1989
  - The Myth of the Failure of Woman Suffrage, Peyton, Janet, 1989
  - The Most Noble of Professions Finds a Spirit of Adventure: Sixty-five North American Women Teachers in Domingo Sarmiento's Argentina of the Late Nineteenth Century, Brophy, Katharine, 1990
  - The Effects of Measles Upon the Health of the Confederate Army of Northern Virginia: 1861-1862, Gibbs, Thomas, 1990
  - Before the Fall: Slave-Owning Women and their World, Montgomerie, Deborah, 1990
  - The Civil War as Seen by Sarah Morgan, Elsberg, David L., 1991
  - Pond's and the Woman of the Twenties, Lee, Christine D., 1991
  - The gleam in her eye reflects the glisten on her lips…: Eye and Lip Cosmetic Advertisements from 1961 to 1971, Trezza, Vanessa L., 1991
  - To the uplift of all, white or black? Reconsidering Amy Morris Bradley's Wilmington Mission and White Education in Reconstruction North Carolina, Yuhl, Stephanie E., 1991
  - Miss Bradley Will Be Mistress Before Anyone Will Be Master: The Singlehood and Independent Spirit of Amy Morris Bradley, Bauerlein, Valerie, 1992
  - Three Women of the War: Their Leadership and Words, Laskey, Catherine V., 1992
  - Greenhands: A History of Local 10 of the Food, Tobacco, and Agricultural Allied Workers of America in Greenville, NC, 1946, Windham, Lane, 1992
  - Jemima Lea Wilson: A Victorian Woman and the Feminine Ideal, Allen, Marni L., 1993
  - Soul to Soul, Arwood, Susannah L., 1993
  - Ample Power in the North: J. B. Duke, American Cyanamid, and the Industrial Development of the Saguenay River, 1923-25, Massell, David P., 1993
  - How the Other Half Lived: Maria Dyer Davies in the World of Southern Woman, 1851Sterne, Evelyn A., 1993
  - The Toll of Toil: Small Farming and Western Migration in the Upper South, 1840-1870, LaVerne, Darren A., 1994
  - Duke Latin MS 112: An Historical and Paleographic Survey, DeHoratius, Edmund F., 1995 (Box 2)
  - The Gruesome Muse: The Revenger's Tragedy and the Emblem Tradition, Longfellow, Erica D., 1995
  - Charity Begins at Home: Moral Responsibility and the World Traveller, Wilkinson, Patrick T., 1995
  - Infidels to the Slaveholders' Religion: Nineteenth-Century Religious Instructions to Southern Slaves, Grove, Tara L., 1996
  - Race, Gender, and Riot: The Wilmington, North Carolina, White Supremacy Campaign of 1898, Kirshenbaum, Andrea, 1996
  - Yankee Schoolmarms in the Reconstruction South: Northern Women and Freedmen's Education in the 1860's, Phillips, Allison D., 1996
  - An Annotated Translation of the Sermon for the Vigil of the Epiphany, Monten, Joshua L., 1997
  - Drawing Nigh and Pressing Forward: A Study of the Significance of the African Methodist Episcopal Church in the 1890s, Rohrs, John D., 1997
  - From Ivy to Kudzu: Regional Consciousness and the Movement for a Southern Education, Young, Neil J., 1997
  - Breaking the Ties: The Separation of Black and White Churches in North Carolina after the Civil War, Legha, Rupinder, 1998
  - Socks and Democracy: The Industrial Democracy Plan of the Durham Hosery Mills, Levinson Wilk, Dan, 1999
  - Plantations and Pens: A Case Study of an Eighteenth Century Slave Community in Jamaica, Manigault, LeRhonda, 1999
  - Access to Credit in the Jim Crow South, McIlvenna, Noeleen, 1999
  - Degrees of Displacement: The Colonial Worlds of Sir Anthony and Lady Jeanie Musgrave, Breen, Deborah F., 2000
  - The Structural Changes of the American Family over a Century: What Advertising Cookbooks Can Teach Us about Gender Roles, Dallis, Isis, 2000
  - T. Lucreti Cari De Rerum NaturaBook I.62-101: Edited with Apparatus, Translation, and Commentary, West, Taylor, 2000
  - The Spirituality of a Young Methodist Woman: The Unpublished Diary of Maria Dyer Davies, 1850-1856, Drake, Para Lee Rodenhizer, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Shop Talk: Southern African-American Beauty Parlors as Public Space, 1900-1955, Roberts, Kathleen Blain, 2001
  - Southern Sisterhood: The Homosocial World of Antebellum Plantation Mistresses, Taranto, Stacie, 2001
  - The North Carolina Mutual and Provident Association: The Methods and Portrayal of its Early Success, Bagford, Kimberly, 2002
  - Obedient Love is Present Heaven: Christian Perfection in the Letters of Sarah Crosby's Letterbook, Hawkins, Patricia, 2002
  - Altering the Southern Lady: The Civil War and its Effects on the Identity of Elite Confederate Women, Lambert, Lara, 2002
  - Before the Atlantic Voyage: An Inquiry into the Business of Slave Trading during the Late Eighteenth Century, Rupert, Linda M., 2002
  - Come On, We Have Room for All Who Come: The Migrant Experience in Durham circa 1880, Schewel, Matt, 2002
  - NO PAPERS, 2003
  - 7UP Advertising in History: Society's Mirror?, Collins, Andrew J., 2004
  - Foreign Students in Germany, 1938, Dittmar, Kerstin, 2004
  - Ophelia Revived: Teen Girls Find Their Voice Through Zines, O'Brien, Margaret, 2004
  - Social Prescription and Separate Spheres in the Journal of Julia Nash Young, Weidemeyer, Susan E., 2004
  - Beyond the Confessional: An Exploration of Gender in the Bocanegra Manuscript, Birkhofer, Melissa D., Kimberly J. Buehring, Diane R. Garbow, Deborah Ann Palacios, Russelle E. Passino, 2005
  - The Manuscript as Art: A Visual Analysis of Literary Manuscripts, Dinin, Aaron P., 2005
  - Lessons in Company Image: The American Tobacco Company in Asia, Lin, Christopher, 2005
  - What Every Girl Should Know: NOTHING! By Order of the Post-Office Department, Shea, Lauren, 2005
  - The Commonwealth: Discipline, Race, and the Voice of Faulkner's Absalom, Absalom!, Smith, Caleb J., 2005
  - Organizing Expansion: How the J. Walter Thompson Company came to reflect the organizational structure and operation of its client during the General Motors Expansion into Latin America, Stern, Jeffrey, 2005
  - Lollipop Power Takes on Sex Role Sterotypes, Barnwell, Stephanie, 2006
  - Walt Whitman, Patriot or Activist? A Contemporary Political Introduction, Knox, Andrea, 2006
  - Redefining African American Activism: Finding a Place for Helen G. Edmonds, Turner, Felicity M., 2006
  - Duke Latin Manuscript 123, Ward, Laura and Curt J. Butera, 2006
  - Whitman's Home-Grown Poem, Davis, Kristen R., 2007 (Box 4)
  - La Theorie et La Pratique du Jardinage: An Examination of 18th Century French Formal Garden Design Through the Writings of Dezailler d'Argenville, Fravel, Laura E., 2007
  - The James Fowler Rusling papers: Navigating Civil War Pension Claims in Post-bellum America, McKeever, Madeline, 2007
  - Ideological Tidal Waves in the Caribbean: The Hatian Revolution and Its Effects on the United States and Virginia, 1791-1810, Singer, Daniel R., 2007
  - American Advertising Regulation and Children from Johnson to Reagan: The Power and Limits of Public Interest Advocacy Groups, Yang, Julie A., 2007
  - Voicing Women and War, Allison, Rachel Chelsea, 2008
  - Uniting a Dismembered State: Secessionist Insurgency in North Carolina, November 1860-May 1861, Hauptfuhrer, Foster Barnes, 2008
  - Duke University's Board of Trustees: A University-Industrial Complex, Cooper, Lindsay M., 2009
  - It Pays to Advertise: Decentraliztion, International Expansion, and GM's Advertising Practices in the Early 20th Century, Dabaghi, Kendall R., 2009
  - Black Hospitals as an Avenue for Social Change: A Narrative of the Life of a Segregated Institution in the New South: Lincoln Hospital, Durham, North Carolina, Daniel, Catherine L., 2009
  - The Names Have Not Changed: The Story of Caswell County Methodism, Hunter, Martin Park, 2009
  - The Miscommunications and Misunderstandings of Nicholas Georgescu-Roegen, Iglesias, Samuel Lee, 2009
  - Calvin Bryce Hoover and the Soviet Union: A Study of the Origins of a Seminal Work on the Soviet Economic System, Rivers, Gregory F., 2009
  - Segregation or Exclusion?: Migrant Children's Schooling in Hidalgo County, Texas, Rodriguez, Anayansi, 2009
  - Free Speech and Freeing Speech: Intradialectal Variation and Identity Construction in the Context of the Civil Rights Movement, Stefanczyk, Dana, 2009
  - Speak Softly and Carry a Lipstick: Government Influence on Female Sexuality through Cosmetics During WWII, Niederriter, Adrienne, 2010
  - Demonstrations in the House of God: Methodist Preaching and the Civil Rights Movement in North Carolina, 1960-1969, Scott, Bonnie, 2010
  - A New Self-Respect and a New Consciousness of Power: White Nurses, Black Soldiers, and the Danger of World War I, Craddock, Hannah C., 2010
  - Remembering Our Roots: Finding the Origins of Race Relations at Duke, Xie, Jianing, 2011
  - The ALFA Female: Sexuality and Separatism, Coalition Building and Counterculture in the Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance, Isard, Risa, 2011
  - Winning papers from 2012-forward have been submitted electronically and can be found on DukeSpace. Please consult Research Services for more information.